{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Any number with an exponent of zero is equal to:", "opta": "zero", "optb": "one", "optc": "that number", "optd": "ten", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the decimal numbering system, what is the MSD?", "opta": "The middle digit of a stream of numbers", "optb": "The digit to the right of the decimal point", "optc": "The last digit on the right", "optd": "The digit with the most weight", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements does NOT describe an advantage of digital technology?", "opta": "The values may vary over a continuous range.", "optb": "The circuits are less affected by noise.", "optc": "The operation can be programmed.", "optd": "Information storage is easy.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The generic array logic (GAL) device is ________.", "opta": "one-time programmable", "optb": "reprogrammable", "optc": "a CMOS device", "optd": "reprogrammable and a CMOS device", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of voltages between VL(max) and VH(min) are ________.", "opta": "unknown", "optb": "unnecessary", "optc": "unacceptable", "optd": "between 2 V and 5 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a digital-to-analog converter?", "opta": "It takes the digital information from an audio CD and converts it to a usable form.", "optb": "It allows the use of cheaper analog techniques, which are always simpler.", "optc": "It stores digital data on a hard drive.", "optd": "It converts direct current to alternating current.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A DAC converts an abstract finite-precision number (usually a fixed-point binary number) into a concrete physical quantity (e.g., a voltage or a pressure)."}, {"question": "What are the symbols used to represent digits in the binary number system?", "opta": "0,1", "optb": "0,1,2", "optc": "0 through 8", "optd": "1,2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A full subtracter circuit requires ________.", "opta": "two inputs and two outputs", "optb": "two inputs and three outputs", "optc": "three inputs and one output", "optd": "three inputs and two outputs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an AND gate is LOW ________.", "opta": "all the time", "optb": "when any input is LOW", "optc": "when any input is HIGH", "optd": "when all inputs are HIGH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Give the decimal value of binary 10010.", "opta": "610", "optb": "910", "optc": "1810", "optd": "2010", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Parallel format means that:", "opta": "each digital signal has its own conductor.", "optb": "several digital signals are sent on each conductor.", "optc": "both binary and hexadecimal can be used.", "optd": "no clock is needed.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A decoder converts ________.", "opta": "noncoded information into coded form", "optb": "coded information into noncoded form", "optc": "HIGHs to LOWs", "optd": "LOWs to HIGHs", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A DAC changes ________.", "opta": "an analog signal into digital data", "optb": "digital data into an analog signal", "optc": "digital data into an amplified signal", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NOT gate is HIGH when ________.", "opta": "the input is LOW", "optb": "the input is HIGH", "optc": "the input changes from LOW to HIGH", "optd": "voltage is removed from the gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an OR gate is LOW when ________.", "opta": "all inputs are LOW", "optb": "any input is LOW", "optc": "any input is HIGH", "optd": "all inputs are HIGH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an analog device?", "opta": "Thermocouple", "optb": "Current flow in a circuit", "optc": "Light switch", "optd": "Audio microphone", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A demultiplexer has ________.", "opta": "one data input and a number of selection inputs, and they have several outputs", "optb": "one input and one output", "optc": "several inputs and several outputs", "optd": "several inputs and one output", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A flip-flop has ________.", "opta": "one stable state", "optb": "no stable states", "optc": "two stable states", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Digital signals transmitted on a single conductor (and a ground) must be transmitted in:", "opta": "slow speed.", "optb": "parallel.", "optc": "analog.", "optd": "serial.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a certain digital waveform, the period is four times the pulse width. The duty cycle is ________.", "opta": "0%", "optb": "25%", "optc": "50%", "optd": "100%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In positive logic, ________.", "opta": "a HIGH = 1, a LOW = 0", "optb": "a LOW = 1, a HIGH = 0", "optc": "only HIGHs are present", "optd": "only LOWs are present", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional binary number 0000.1010 to decimal.", "opta": "0.625", "optb": "0.50", "optc": "0.55", "optd": "0.10", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Digital representations of numerical values of quantities may BEST be described as having characteristics:", "opta": "that are difficult to interpret because they are continuously changing.", "optb": "that vary constantly over a continuous range of values.", "optc": "that vary in constant and direct proportion to the values they represent.", "optd": "that vary in discrete steps in proportion to the values they represent.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A common instrument used in troubleshooting a digital circuit is a(n) ________.", "opta": "logic probe", "optb": "oscilloscope", "optc": "pulser", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The parallel transmission of digital data:", "opta": "is much slower than the serial transmission of data.", "optb": "requires only one signal line between sender and receiver.", "optc": "requires as many signal lines between sender and receiver as there are data bits.", "optd": "is less expensive than the serial method of data transmission.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional decimal number 6.75 to binary.", "opta": "0111.1100", "optb": "0110.1010", "optc": "0110.1100", "optd": "0110.0110", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is one relative disadvantage of serial transfer?", "opta": "It requires too many conductors.", "optb": "Its interconnect system is complex.", "optc": "It is slow.", "optd": "It can only be used over very short distances.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which format requires fewer conductors?", "opta": "Parallel", "optb": "Serial", "optc": "Both are the same", "optd": "Cannot tell", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A pulse has a period of 15 ms. Its frequency is ________.", "opta": "6.66 Hz", "optb": "66.66 Hz", "optc": "666.66 Hz", "optd": "15 Hz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Give the decimal value of binary 10000110.", "opta": "13410", "optb": "14410", "optc": "11010", "optd": "12610", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rise time is the time it takes a pulse to go from ________.", "opta": "the base line to the maximum HIGH voltage", "optb": "10% of the pulse amplitude to the maximum HIGH voltage", "optc": "the base line to 90% of the pulse amplitude", "optd": "10% of the pulse amplitude to 90% of the pulse amplitude", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an analog-to-digital converter?", "opta": "It makes digital signals.", "optb": "It takes analog signals and puts them in digital format.", "optc": "It allows the use of digital signals in everyday life.", "optd": "It stores information on a CD.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A multiplexer has ________.", "opta": "one input and several outputs", "optb": "one input and one output", "optc": "several inputs and several outputs", "optd": "several inputs and one output", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the decimal value of 23 ?", "opta": "2", "optb": "4", "optc": "6", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "23  = 2*2*2=8"}, {"question": "An encoder converts ________.", "opta": "noncoded information into coded form", "optb": "coded information into noncoded form", "optc": "HIGHs to LOWs", "optd": "LOWs to HIGHs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What kind of logic device or circuit is used to store information?", "opta": "Counter", "optb": "Register", "optc": "Inverter", "optd": "Buffer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PLCC packages have leads on ________.", "opta": "one side", "optb": "two sides", "optc": "three sides", "optd": "four sides", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the typical invalid voltage for a binary signal?", "opta": "0.7\u20132.8 volts", "optb": "0.8\u20133 volts", "optc": "0.8\u20132 volts", "optd": "0.7\u20132.5 volts", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional binary number 0001.0010 to decimal.", "opta": "1.40", "optb": "1.125", "optc": "1.20", "optd": "1.80", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional binary number 10010.0100 to decimal.", "opta": "24.50", "optb": "18.25", "optc": "18.40", "optd": "16.25", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many binary bits are necessary to represent 748 different numbers?", "opta": "9", "optb": "7", "optc": "10", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A periodic digital waveform has a pulse width (tw) of 6 ms and a period (T) of 18 ms. The duty cycle is ________.", "opta": "3.3%", "optb": "33.3%", "optc": "6%", "optd": "18%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Any number with an exponent of one is equal to:", "opta": "zero.", "optb": "one.", "optc": "two.", "optd": "that number.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Serial format means digital signals are:", "opta": "sent over many conductors simultaneously.", "optb": "sent over one conductor sequentially.", "optc": "sent in groups of eight signals.", "optd": "sent in binary coded decimal.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the decimal value of 2\u20131 ?", "opta": "0.5", "optb": "0.25", "optc": "0.05", "optd": "0.1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which format can send several bits of information faster?", "opta": "Parallel", "optb": "Serial", "optc": "Both are the same", "optd": "Cannot tell", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The frequency of a pulse train is 2 kHz. The pulse period is ________.", "opta": "5 ms", "optb": "50 ms", "optc": "500 s", "optd": "2 s", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What has happened to the advances in digital technologies over the past three decades?", "opta": "Slowed down considerably", "optb": "Continued to increase, but at a decreasing rate", "optc": "Made excellent progress", "optd": "Nothing short of phenomenal", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A type of digital circuit technology that uses bipolar junction transistors is ________.", "opta": "TTL", "optb": "CMOS", "optc": "LSI", "optd": "NMOS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many unique symbols are used in the decimal number system?", "opta": "One", "optb": "Nine", "optc": "Ten", "optd": "Unlimited", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A classification of ICs with complexities of 12 to 100 equivalent gates on a chip is known as ________.", "opta": "SSI", "optb": "MSI", "optc": "LSI", "optd": "VLSI", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a semiconductor memory?", "opta": "RAM", "optb": "MAR", "optc": "CD-ROM", "optd": "CD", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The holes through a PC board are ________.", "opta": "smaller with SMT than with through-hole mounting", "optb": "larger with SMT than with through-hole mounting", "optc": "the same size as with through-hole mounting", "optd": "usually unnecessary", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A classification of ICs with complexities of 100 to 10,000 equivalent gates per chip is known as ________.", "opta": "SSI", "optb": "MSI", "optc": "LSI", "optd": "VLSI", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}